<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mitsubishi Colt Galant on Kuruma Stories</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mitsubishi Colt Galant on Kuruma Stories</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mitsubishi Colt Galant AI Custom (1970)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant/cg-rt-mitsubishi-colt-galant-ai-custom-1970/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant/cg-rt-mitsubishi-colt-galant-ai-custom-1970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RT-Mitsubishi-Colt-Galant-AI-Custom-1970.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mitsubishi Colt Galant AI Custom&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; March 1970&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; Very easy-to-drive five-seater sedan. Outstanding performance in its class, very smooth and well-balanced powertrain, slightly low-geared, generally quiet, exhaust system resonance increases at medium speeds, drum brakes prone to fade if used frequently, very comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Mitsubishi Colt Galant AI Custom&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 1289cc Galant AI comes in four variations: the lowest-priced Standard (518,000 yen), the Deluxe (568,000 yen), the Custom (596,000 yen) with heat-absorbing glass and reclining seats, and the Sports (636,000 yen) with disc brakes in the front, wood-rimmed steering wheel, and round gauges. The car we tested this time was the Custom purchased by C/G for long-term testing, which had only been driven about 2,000km at the time of this writing. In other words, it was still a brand-new car. We were reluctant to bring a car that was not yet fully run-in to Yatabe and conduct top-speed testing (we often have to make such unreasonable demands to meet the tight schedule of the magazine), but to our surprise, this AI not only withstood the testing without complaint, but also proved that the performance data claimed by the manufacturer is not at all exaggerated. That is, the maximum speed measured over a 1km straight section was 147.0km/h (145km/h in the catalog), and the 0-400m acceleration was 18.6 seconds (18.3 seconds in the catalog), which is an outstanding dynamic performance for a pure family sedan in the 1300cc class.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitsubishi Colt Galant AII GS (1970)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant/cg-rt-mitsubishi-colt-galant-aii-gs-1970/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant/cg-rt-mitsubishi-colt-galant-aii-gs-1970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RT-Mitsubishi-Colt-Galant-AII-GS-1970.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mitsubishi Colt Galant AII GS&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; March 1970&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; High performance version of the Galant, SOHC 1.5-liter engine, revs smoothly up to over 7000rpm, extremely responsive across the entire range, extremely good fuel economy, variable ratio steering with good response, handling generally excellent, but with standard tires it tends to oversteer early, good value for money.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Mitsubishi Colt Galant AII GS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Colt Galant, a strategic model with which Mitsubishi Heavy Industries dared to challenge the 1300-1600cc market, which is the most competitive not only in Japan but also internationally, got off to a good start with 6,400 units sold in December when it was released.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Galant is available in two models: the AI with a 1.3-liter engine, and the AII with a 1.5-liter engine, sharing a common four-door sedan body. The lineup is further divided into seven variations, with minor differences in specifications. The AII GS (Grand Sport) that we tested is the highest-performance sports sedan model, and is also the most expensive (711,000 yen).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
