<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kuruma Stories</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant-fto/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kuruma Stories</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant-fto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mitsubishi Colt Galant FTO GIII vs. Toyota Sprinter SR (1972)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant-fto/cg-gt-mitsubishi-colt-galant-fto-giii-vs-toyota-sprinter-sr-1972/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant-fto/cg-gt-mitsubishi-colt-galant-fto-giii-vs-toyota-sprinter-sr-1972/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-GT-Mitsubishi-Colt-Galant-FTO-GIII-vs-Toyota-Sprinter-SR-1972.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mitsubishi Colt Galant FTO GIII&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Group Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; February 1972&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Comparison test: Mitsubishi Galant FTO GIII vs. Toyota Sprinter SR&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month, we compared two 1400cc sports cars, the Toyota Sprinter SR and the Mitsubishi Galant FTO GIII, under a variety of conditions, including performance testing at Yatabe. We would like to begin by briefly explaining why we chose these two models from the many cars in the same class. First, the Sprinter SR boasts the best specs in its class, making it a natural choice for pure motoring enthusiasts like us (and we think many C/G readers share our priorities), so we unanimously agreed that it should be included. Second, the Galant FTO GIII was just recently released on the market, and since we drove the GII last month and were impressed with its handling, we were particularly interested in how the GIII, which has 9ps more power, would stack up, so we included it as well. When we think of Sprinters, the Nissan Sunny GX also immediately comes to mind. In our opinion, however, the Sunny Coupe 1200GX is the best of the Sunny model range, and the Excellent, with its SOHC 1400cc engine, is a donwngrade in every respect (except for having a brake servo), so we deliberately left it out of this comparison test. To avoid any misunderstanding, we should add that the C/G test is first and foremost a test of driving performance, and places particular emphasis on the balance of maneuverability and braking power with power performance, especially when it comes to cars that are marketed as being sporty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
