<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kuruma Stories</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant-fto/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kuruma Stories</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant-fto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mitsubishi Colt Galant FTO GIII vs. Toyota Sprinter SR (1972)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant-fto/cg-gt-mitsubishi-colt-galant-fto-giii-vs-toyota-sprinter-sr-1972/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mitsubishi/colt-galant-fto/cg-gt-mitsubishi-colt-galant-fto-giii-vs-toyota-sprinter-sr-1972/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-GT-Mitsubishi-Colt-Galant-FTO-GIII-vs-Toyota-Sprinter-SR-1972.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mitsubishi Colt Galant FTO GIII&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Group Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; February 1972&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Comparison test: Mitsubishi Galant FTO GIII vs. Toyota Sprinter SR&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month, we comparatively tested two 1400cc sports cars, the Toyota Sprinter SR and the Mitsubishi Galant FTO GIII, under a variety of conditions, including on the Yatabe test course. I would like to briefly explain why we chose these two models from the many cars in the same class. The Sprinter SR is the best in its class in terms of specs, and is the best for those of us who just enjoy motoring (and I think this includes many C/G readers), so we chose it without question. The Galant GTO GIII has just been released, and since I drove the GII last month and was impressed with its handling, I was particularly interested in how the GIII, which has 9ps more power, would behave, so I added it. When I think of Sprinters, the Nissan Sunny GX also immediately comes to mind. In our opinion, though, the Sunny Coupe 1200GX is best, and the Excellent, which has had its engine replaced with a SOHC 1400, is a donwngrade in every aspect (except for the brake servo), so we deliberately left it out of this comparison. To avoid any misunderstanding, we should add that the C/G test is first and foremost a test of &amp;ldquo;driving&amp;rdquo; performance, and we place importance on the balance of maneuverability and braking power that matches the power performance. This is especially true of cars that are marketed as being sporty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
