<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mazda Luce Rotary Coupe on Kuruma Stories</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mazda/luce-rotary-coupe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mazda Luce Rotary Coupe on Kuruma Stories</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 04:50:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mazda/luce-rotary-coupe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mazda Luce Rotary Coupe (1969)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mazda/luce-rotary-coupe/cg-ri-mazda-luce-rotary-coupe-1969/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mazda/luce-rotary-coupe/cg-ri-mazda-luce-rotary-coupe-1969/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RI-Mazda-Luce-Rotary-Coupe-1969.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mazda Luce Rotary Coupe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Impressions&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; December 1969&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; Shotaro Kobayashi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Luce Rotary Coupe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The third prong of Mazda&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;rotaryization&amp;rdquo; strategy, the Luce Rotary Coupe, was finally released on October 15th. Prior to its announcement to the general public, a test drive was held for the press, going from Tokyo to Hakone and back. This C/G editor, who has now recovered from his leg injury, also participated, so I would like to share my brief impressions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mazda Luce Rotary Coupe (1969)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mazda/luce-rotary-coupe/mf-tdr-mazda-luce-rotary-coupe-1969/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mazda/luce-rotary-coupe/mf-tdr-mazda-luce-rotary-coupe-1969/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/MF-TDR-Mazda-Luce-Rotary-Coupe-1969.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mazda Luce Rotary Coupe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Motor Fan&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Test Drive Report&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; December 1969&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; Katsumi Kageyama&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the Cosmo Sport to the Familia Rotary series, Toyo Kogyo&amp;rsquo;s mission of &amp;ldquo;rotaryization&amp;rdquo; is steadily showing signs of success.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Luce Rotary Coupe is an attempt to further upgrade their rotary technology and apply it to luxury passenger cars. This car, which debuted at the Tokyo Motor Show two years ago under the name RX87, has lines similar to the Luce in appearance, but in terms of overall quality, it should be seen as a car that concentrates all of Toyo Kogyo&amp;rsquo;s technology into one vehicle and serves as the fuse for the upcoming rotary offensive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mazda Luce Hardtop GS II (1973)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mazda/luce-rotary-coupe/cg-rt-mazda-luce-hardtop-gs-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mazda/luce-rotary-coupe/cg-rt-mazda-luce-hardtop-gs-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RT-Mazda-Luce-Rotary-Hardtop-GS-II-1973.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mazda Luce Hardtop GS II&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Impressions&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; April 1973&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; The highest-performance version of the new Luce, a smooth and quiet personal luxury car. Despite its attractive specs, maneuverability is only average among domestic cars, while ride comfort and livability are excellent. As with the AP model, fuel economy is poor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Luce Hardtop GS II&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new Mazda Luce series was just announced last October, and for this report, we tested the top-of-the-line, high-performance hardtop GS II over a distance of about 850km. We had already had the opportunity to test drive this model for a short time immediately after its announcement, and were particularly impressed by its handling, which was far superior to that of previous Mazda mass-market cars. In the road test in last month&amp;rsquo;s issue, we covered the sedan GR AP model, which is equipped with a thermal reactor for exhaust emission control, which is currently a hot topic. Contrary to what you might imagine from the &amp;ldquo;emissions-controlled&amp;rdquo; label, the engine in that car produces effective power, and the excellent automatic transmission is well matched to it. Another thing that made a strong impression was the well-balanced chassis, even when fitted with ordinary 6.45-13-4PR bias-ply tires on 5J x 13-inch wheels (which are still on the wide side for a Japanese passenger car).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
