<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Toyota Celica on Kuruma Stories</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/toyota/celica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Toyota Celica on Kuruma Stories</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/toyota/celica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Toyota Celica 1600GT (1971)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/toyota/celica/cg-ri-toyota-celica-1600gt-1971/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/toyota/celica/cg-ri-toyota-celica-1600gt-1971/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RI-Toyota-Celica-1600GT-1971.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toyota Celica 1600GT&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Impressions&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; January 1971&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Toyota Celica 1600GT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The day after testing Toyota&amp;rsquo;s new Carina 1600ST, I had the opportunity to drive the Celica GT for just three hours, so I’ll share my impressions while keeping them brief. The Celica is a sporty two-door hardtop that shares its floorpan, suspension, and powertrain with the Carina. The aim is to enable users to create a semi-customized vehicle—starting with a long-nose, short-deck bodyshell, a Japanese version of the so-called “specialty car” that became a hit in the US with the Mustang and in Europe with the Capri—with a choice of four exterior options, four engines, and nine interior options, all of which are computer-calculated and delivered within a short lead time, according to a Toyota PR spokesperson. In addition to the three engines shared with the Carina, the Celica also offers a GT model with a unique DOHC 1588cc 115ps engine and 5-speed gearbox.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toyota Celica 1600GT vs. Mitsubishi Colt Galant GTO MR (1971)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/toyota/celica/cg-gt-toyota-celica-1600gt-vs-mitsubishi-colt-galant-gto-mr-1971/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/toyota/celica/cg-gt-toyota-celica-1600gt-vs-mitsubishi-colt-galant-gto-mr-1971/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-GT-Mitsubishi-Colt-Galant-GTO-MR-1971.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mitsubishi Colt Galant GTO MR&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Group Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; April 1971&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Comparison test: Toyota Celica GT vs. Mitsubishi Galant GTO MR&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mitsubishi&amp;rsquo;s Galant GTO MR and Toyota&amp;rsquo;s Celica GT are very similar in both specifications and character, and are five-seater sports coupes that appeared at roughly the same time, targeting the same market. Both are equipped with 1.6-liter DOHC engines and 5-speed gearboxes, and there is almost no difference beween them in terms of external dimensions or weight. Structurally, both cars are very orthodox, with a monocoque hardtop body based on the chassis of a mass-market sedan (the GTO is based on the Galant AI/AII, the Celica on the Carina). Both have a conventional layout with MacPherson strut front suspensions and rigid axles at the rear, but the rear suspensions differ in design; the GTO series is leaf-sprung, and only the most powerful MR model has a torque rod added, while the Celica&amp;rsquo;s is suspended by coil springs, with four longitudinal links and lateral location via a Panhard rod.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toyota Celica 1600GTV vs. Nissan Bluebird U 1600SSS-E (1972)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/toyota/celica/cg-gt-nissan-bluebird-u-1600-sss-e-vs-toyota-celica-gtv-1972/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/toyota/celica/cg-gt-nissan-bluebird-u-1600-sss-e-vs-toyota-celica-gtv-1972/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-GT-Nissan-Bluebird-U-1600-SSS-E-vs-Toyota-Celica-GTV-1972.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nissan Bluebird U 1600SSS-E&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Group Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; November 1972&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Comparison test: Toyota Celica 1600GTV vs. Nissan Bluebird U 1600SSS-E&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Celica GT and the Bluebird U 1600 SSS compete in the same market in terms of character and price class, and recently variations noteworthy for enthusiasts have been added to both series, namely the Celica GTV and Bluebird U Hardtop 1600 SSS-E featured in this comparison test. Both are equipped with 115ps engines and 5-speed gearboxes, but the Bluebird&amp;rsquo;s hardtop body is slightly larger and weighs about 60kg more. Needless to say, the Celica GTV is equipped with a DOHC 1588cc engine and two Mikuni Solex 40PHH twin-choke carburetors, while the Bluebird U 1600 SSS-E is equipped with the same Bosch electronic fuel injection as its big brother, the 1800 SSS-E. As mentioned above, both cars have an output of 115ps, but the power peak is 6400rpm for the Celica and 6200rpm for the Bluebird, and the maximum torque is 14.5kgm/5200 and 14.6kgm/4400rpm, respectively, so it can be said that the DOHC Celica is a higher-revving car.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
