<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Isuzu 117 Coupe on Kuruma Stories</title>
    <link>http://example.org/isuzu/117-coupe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Isuzu 117 Coupe on Kuruma Stories</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.org/isuzu/117-coupe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Isuzu 117 Coupe (1970)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/isuzu/117-coupe/cg-rt-isuzu-117-coupe-1970/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/isuzu/117-coupe/cg-rt-isuzu-117-coupe-1970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.org/images/CG-RT-Isuzu-117-Coupe-1970.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Isuzu 117 Coupe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Impressions&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; January 1970&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Isuzu 117 Coupe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Isuzu-Ghia Design 117 Coupe, which debuted at the Tokyo Motor Show two years ago, showed no signs of going into production, raising concerns that it would be a mere show model destined for a brief, beautiful life. However, looking back, we can see that an intense development process had been quietly and tirelessly continuing behind the scenes over the past two years. Having thoroughly tested the now-released Isuzu 117 Coupe over a 500km drive, we realized that the two-year wait was not in vain. Some manufacturers reluctantly release vehicles still in the &amp;ldquo;prototype&amp;rdquo; stage of development due to demands from sales departments. Other car designers are not afraid to publicly declare that they would not be afraid to buy such a car immediately after its release. However, the attitude of the people involved in the design and production of the Isuzu 117 Coupe is, in a sense, unconventional, and conscientious. Until their conscience as engineers convinced them, they refused to put a &amp;ldquo;half-baked&amp;rdquo; car into production, no matter how strong the demands of the sales department.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
