<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Honda 1300 on Kuruma Stories</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/honda/honda-1300/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Honda 1300 on Kuruma Stories</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/honda/honda-1300/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Honda 1300 77 Deluxe (1970)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/honda/honda-1300/cg-rt-honda-1300-77-deluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/honda/honda-1300/cg-rt-honda-1300-77-deluxe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RT-Honda-1300-77-Deluxe-1970.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Honda 1300 77 Deluxe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; February 1970&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; Air-cooled four-cylinder, powerful, smooth up to 8000rpm, low noise level even at high revolutions, power performance comparable to a 1600cc GT, poor fuel economy, worrying handling a cause for concern, unsatisfactory heater and demister.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Honda 1300 77 Deluxe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few cars have been as controversial in recent years as the Honda 1300. Technically, it is an ambitious design that features a powerful, double-wall air-cooled, dry-sump lubricated four-cylinder engine, mounted transversely and driving the front wheels, following in the footsteps of the ill-fated Honda F1 racing car, the RA302, and attracted the attention of engineers both in Japan and abroad. However, for two or three months after its release on April 15 last year, the Honda 1300 had still not appeared on the streets. At the time, the automotive world was abuzz with the issue of defective cars, and dark rumors were circulating that the 1300 might also be part of the problem (in reality, it was said that the measures to deal with the &amp;ldquo;defects&amp;rdquo; in the N360 had disrupted the production plans for the 1300, and so the design staff and factory personnel were temporarily diverted to that role).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honda 1300 Coupe 9S (1970)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/honda/honda-1300/cg-rt-honda-1300-coupe-9s-1970/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/honda/honda-1300/cg-rt-honda-1300-coupe-9s-1970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RT_Honda-1300-Coupe-9S-1970.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Honda 1300 Coupe 9S&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; April 1970&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; A highly practical five-seater coupe based on the 1300 sedan. Roominess not inferior to the sedan. Air-cooled engine with four carburetors. Exceptional power. Unibody construction, stiffer suspension than the sedan, chassis finally catching up with the engine. Maneuverability significantly improved over the sedan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Honda 1300 Coupe 9S&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we tested the Honda 1300 77 in the February issue, we were very impressed by its excellent engine, but criticized its chassis for being too weak to support it, and for not being able to safely utilize its great power performance. The 77 Deluxe we tested was a very early production model (chassis number H1300-1000611) that was purchased by C/G for long-term testing, but during the approximately 20,000km we had driven so far, it had frequent problems, so the passion we had initially felt for the Honda 1300 gradually faded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
