<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nissan Fairlady on Kuruma Stories</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/nissan/fairlady/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nissan Fairlady on Kuruma Stories</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/nissan/fairlady/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Datsun Fairlady 2000 (1969)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nissan/fairlady/cg-rt-datsun-fairlady-2000-1969/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nissan/fairlady/cg-rt-datsun-fairlady-2000-1969/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RT-Datsun-Fairlady-2000-1969.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Datsun Fairlady 2000&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; April 1969&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; Classic two-seater sports car, brutal and dynamic, four-cylinder 2-liter engine, powerful but rough, 5-speed gearbox, strong brakes but requires hard pedal force, extremely maneuverable but requires good road surface, weather-resistant hardtop, very noisy and extremely hard ride.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Fairlady 2000&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this 1970s society, where men are becoming increasingly feminized and &amp;ldquo;sports cars&amp;rdquo; are no longer sports cars, the Datsun Fairlady is becoming a truly rare creation. From a technical standpoint, it is &amp;ldquo;old-fashioned&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; in every respect. The Fairlady appeared in 1961, but its design, which is clearly represented by its separate ladder frame and rigid rear axle, belongs to the same generation as the Triumph TR2/3 and MGA of the 1950s. Of course, through the constant development process, the Fairlady has come to have outstanding power performance and appropriate maneuverability for a 2-liter sports car today, but in order to achieve this, &amp;ldquo;luxuries&amp;rdquo; such as a comfortable ride and roominess have been completely rejected. It is a sports car for sports that does not tolerate compromise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nissan Fairlady Z432 (1970)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nissan/fairlady/cg-rt-nissan-fairlady-z432-1970/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nissan/fairlady/cg-rt-nissan-fairlady-z432-1970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RT-Nissan-Fairlady-Z432-1970.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nissan Fairlady Z432&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; February 1970&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; A practical two-seater GT with a DOHC six-cylinder engine based on the R380. More flexible at slower speeds than the GTR, extremely economical when using fifth gear, bias-ply tires. Very good handling, good support from bucket seats, excellent heater and ventilation, high price.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Fairlady Z432&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Fairlady Z, announced in December 1969, comes in three models: the popular Z (930,000 yen), equipped with the same basic 1988cc SOHC, six-cylinder, 130ps/6000rpm engine as the Skyline GT; the Z-L (1,080,000 yen), fitted with a 5-speed gearbox and deluxe interior equipment; and the high-performance Z432 (1,850,000), equipped with the same 1989cc DOHC, six-cylinder, 160ps/7000rpm engine as the Skyline GT-R, which is based on the engine of the R380.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nissan Fairlady 240ZG (1972)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nissan/fairlady/cg-rt-nissan-fairlady-240zg-1972/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 04:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nissan/fairlady/cg-rt-nissan-fairlady-240zg-1972/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/CG-RT-Nissan-Fairlady-240ZG-1972.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nissan Fairlady 240ZG&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; Car Graphic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Format:&lt;/b&gt; Road Test&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; March 1972&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Author:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;C/G Test Group&amp;rdquo; (uncredited)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; The Z has been enlarged to 2.4 liters, and compared to the 2-liter model, the acceleration has improved significantly, and flexibility has increased. If you use fifth gear frequently, the fuel economy is good. In other respects, it is the same as the conventional model. The disadvantage of being prone to clutch slip is the same.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Road testing the Fairlady 240ZG&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the Fairlady Z debuted in December 1969, C/G has tested various models from time to time. First, we did a full test of the DOHC 2-liter 160ps Z432 at Yatabe (C/G, February 1972), then we drove the race-spec 240Z (the SCCN team car Z432R equipped with a SOHC 2.4-liter engine tuned to 200+ps) at FISCO (C/G, June 1971), then, when the domestic 240Z was officially released, we tested the automatic model, which we had never tried before (C/G, January 1972). We also went to Yatabe to test the 240ZG with a five-speed gearbox for last month&amp;rsquo;s issue, but unfortunately, the valve gear was damaged and we had to stop the test. So, early in the new year, we tried it again with a different 240ZG.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
